Marie Laborde

www.linkedin.com/in/marielaborde https://github.com/mjoulel mjoulel@sbcglobal.net

Objective

I would like the opportunity to apply my technical knowledge and strong analytical, communication, research, and writing skills in order to contribute to your company's success. My knowledge of HTML5, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, and AJAX may also prove to be beneficial to your company. My dependability and personal persistence have been major factors in meeting professional goals.

Technical Skills

Hardware: PC, RS/6000, Power 4 - Power 7

Software: BestQuest, Rational Quality Manager (RQM), CMVC (Configuration

Management and Version Control), AUSTEXT, RETAIN, DCE / DFS,

Freelance

Networking: TCP / IP, Ethernet

Scripting: HTML/HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Express.js, Node.js, MySQL,

Kornshell, Bash, AJAX

Certifications: ATE (AIX Technical Expert)

EDUCATION

B.S., Computer Science – Montclair State University, Upper Montclair, NJ

Professional Experience

Benefit Services Representative

The Boon Group – Austin, TX

July 2016 - Present

Provided customer service by responding to inbound calls and assisted with department overflow.

- Shared knowledge of employee benefits and insurance products within a customer service environment.
- Developed research and problem resolution skills.
- Implemented strong verbal and written interpersonal skills.

Software Test Specialist, ISST (Integrated Software Systems Test) at IBM CTG – Austin, TX July 2015 - December 2015

Prepared UNIX systems for implementing testing programs, software scenarios, regression testing, negative testing, error retests and/or usability. Analyzed software test results using multiple defect tracking system tools.

- Ensured that the operating system, programs and hardware technologies functioned correctly through detailed analysis, problem determination, and collaborating with developers.
- Reduced exposure of software product deficiencies to customers.

- Implemented defect tracking system tools to monitor technical problems, and verify their corresponding fixes to developers.
- Assisted in resolving operating system problems, program malfunctions, and hardware/software configuration issues.

Technical Support Specialist, AIX Remote Technical Support IBM – Austin, TX September 2001 - February 2015

Responded to customers' technical questions and problems with urgency and professionalism, through the delivery of quality results that exceeded expectations.

- Managed and corrected customers' technical problems in a timely manner
- Created quality knowledge content through numerous written technical documents to supplement phone support to customers.
- Exceeded management's goals (in terms of support center metrics).
- Specialized as the team's technical focal point and intermediator for developers and customers.

Software Engineer, ARTLab (AIX APAR Regression Test Lab) IBM – Austin, TX September 1998 - August 2001

Maintained a test environment consisting of 12+ RS/6000 systems and a large set of integrated regression tests, by monitoring test runs, debugging failures, handling hardware problems, updating test cases and documentation.

- Prepared regression tests with system updates, eliminating potential customer problems and enhancing product quality in a timely fashion.
- Developed testing programs that address such areas as regression testing, rerunning tests (due to errors), stress testing, and usability.
- Determined product deficiencies, with opened defects, and working closely with developers to recreate and fix the product deficiencies.
- Collaborated with team members to maintain process documents and quality records in the Department Operating Manual for technical accuracy and compliance.
- Analyzed errors to reevaluate and enhance test coverage, which substantially decreased software product deficiencies.